# MINAHIL NAWAZ

# FRONT END DEVELOPER

# O307 0562260

minahil1323@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/minahil-nawaz-0343691b9



minahilnawaz.github.io

#### SKILLS

HTML5 jQuery, Javascript

CSS3 ReactNative

SCSS Redux

Bootstrap Photoshop

EDUCATION

# **BS Software Engineering**

Punjab University College of Information technology

2017-2021 3.36/4.0

FYP: A Computer Vision based system to determine crop health

\_\_\_\_\_

# INTERESTS

Gaming

Travelling

Music

Seasons

\_\_\_\_\_

### LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

#### ABOUT

Over 2 Years of working experience having good command over Front-End Development.

Having proficient knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SCSS, ReactJS, jQuery, Ionic and many of the CSS frameworks like Bootstrap, Foundation, Semantic UI and google Materialize

Transforming complex layout PSDs into pixel-perfect presentation-layer HTML5/CSS3 templates

Produced multiple visual elements of web application by translating UI/UX design.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Sfcc Front end developer

Systems Limited August, 2021 - Present

- Worked as Sfcc front-end developer
- Exposure of making components in page designer and experience of working in an agile team and transforming figma into pixel-perfect presentation-layer HTML5/CSS3 templates.

#### **React Native Intern**

ShopDev March, 2021 - June, 2021

- Worked as React Native intern.
- Used understanding of React fundamentals to promote better component lifecycle practices and worked on various screens of the Aimfit application.

\_\_\_\_\_

# **PROJECTS**

#### kadewe.de

- Worked on its SFRA implementation on different pages and also created various page designer components.
- Design its loyalty program from scratch.
- Worked on improving site performance by removing redundant code and unused CSS.
- Converted new designs using the following skills · HTML 5 · CSS 3 · SCSS · JQuery · Bootstrap · Webpack.
- Design static pages through page designer and added animations.

#### hautelogic.net

- Convert figma templates into designs using HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript and Bootstrap
- Worked on improving site performance by removing redundant code.
- Produced multiple visual elements of web application.

#### Aimfit

- Translated design and wireframes into high-quality code
- Identified web-based user interactions and developed highly responsive user interface components using ReactNative and Redux.